<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | Q-PACERS (DSMC-RG)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_f05efc27037f3153.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mahfuz Defends Final</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-03-05-mahfuz-defends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-03-05-mahfuz-defends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Mahfuzul Haque for defending MSc. Thesis Titled  “Design Of Silicon-carbide Based Single-quantum-well White LED”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polarization Insensitive Electrically Reconfigurable Meta-Lens for 2 μm Wavelength Published</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-11-11-polarization-insensitive-electrically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-11-11-polarization-insensitive-electrically/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking study titled &amp;ldquo;Polarization Insensitive Electrically Reconfigurable Meta-Lens for 2 μm Wavelength&amp;rdquo; has been published in Optical Materials Express. This research introduces a meta-lens capable of focusing light at a 2 μm wavelength without sensitivity to polarization, enhancing its versatility in optical applications. The lens&amp;rsquo;s electrical reconfigurability allows dynamic adjustments, paving the way for advancements in adaptive optics and infrared imaging systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1364/OME.540435&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DFT Analysis of Strain Effects on Monolayer Silicon Carbide Published</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-09-16-dft-analysis-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-09-16-dft-analysis-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent publication in Physica B: Condensed Matter presents a density functional theory (DFT) analysis titled &amp;ldquo;Investigation of the Physical Properties through Strain Effect of Monolayer Silicon Carbide Material.&amp;rdquo; The study examines how strain influences the mechanical and electronic properties of monolayer silicon carbide (SiC), revealing potential applications in nanoscale devices. Understanding these strain effects is crucial for designing SiC-based components in flexible electronics and sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2024.416670&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigurable Metasurface for Quantum Emitter Control Published</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-09-16-reconfigurable-metasurface-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-09-16-reconfigurable-metasurface-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers have published a paper titled &amp;ldquo;Sb₂S₃/AlGaAs-Based Reconfigurable Metasurface for Dynamic Polarization and Directionality Control of Quantum Emitter Emission&amp;rdquo; in RSC Advances. The study demonstrates a metasurface that can dynamically control the polarization and directionality of light emitted from quantum sources. This innovation holds promise for quantum communication technologies, where precise manipulation of light is essential for information transfer and processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/D4RA03726J&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing Deep Learning and Phase Change Materials for Multifunctional Metasurfaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-09-06-synergizing-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-09-06-synergizing-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study, &amp;ldquo;Synergizing Deep Learning and Phase Change Materials for Four-State Broadband Multifunctional Metasurfaces in the Visible Range,&amp;rdquo; has been published in the Journal of Optics and Laser Technology. The research integrates deep learning algorithms with phase change materials to design metasurfaces capable of multiple functionalities across the visible spectrum. This approach could lead to the development of advanced optical devices with applications in imaging, sensing, and display technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.optlastec.2024.108789&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Scholar Profile Surpasses 1000 Citations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-20-google-scholar-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-08-20-google-scholar-profile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A notable academic milestone has been achieved, with the Google Scholar profile surpassing 1000 citations. This reflects the significant impact and recognition of the research contributions within the scholarly community, highlighting the influence and reach of the published works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.com/citations?user=Fu8Hkb4AAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Md. Ehsanul Karim Successfully Defends MSc Thesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-06-04-md-ehsanul-karim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-06-04-md-ehsanul-karim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Md. Ehsanul Karim for successfully defending his Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. This accomplishment marks a significant step in his academic journey and contributes valuable insights to his field of study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New PG Course on Quantum Photonics and Computing Offered</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-05-09-new-pg-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-05-09-new-pg-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An experimental postgraduate course on Quantum Photonics and Quantum Computing is being offered in the April 2024 semester. This course aims to equip students with foundational knowledge and practical skills in these cutting-edge areas, preparing them for research and development roles in quantum technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/teaching/A2024_EEE6004Q&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Papers Published in ICTP 2023 Proceedings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-05-06-three-papers-published/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-05-06-three-papers-published/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three research papers have been published in the Proceedings of ICTP 2023, showcasing advancements in various technological domains. These publications reflect ongoing research efforts and contributions to the international scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Research Assistant Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-02-17-call-for-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-02-17-call-for-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A call for Research Assistant (RA) applications has been announced for the project &amp;ldquo;RISE-Metalens.&amp;rdquo; This opportunity invites aspiring researchers to contribute to cutting-edge studies in metasurface technologies, offering a platform to engage in innovative research and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/research/RISE-Metalens&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-Lens Design Project Funded by RISE, BUET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-02-17-meta-lens-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-02-17-meta-lens-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project &amp;ldquo;Synergizing Deep Learning and Topology Optimization for Tunable Meta-Lens Design&amp;rdquo; has secured full funding from RISE, BUET. This initiative aims to develop tunable meta-lenses by integrating deep learning techniques with topology optimization, potentially revolutionizing optical device design and functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VO₂-Based All-Optical Reflection Modulator Published</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-01-01-vo-based-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2024-01-01-vo-based-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proceedings from the International Photonic Conference in Florida, USA, include a paper titled &amp;ldquo;VO₂-Based All-Optical Reflection Modulator for 2 μm Wave Band.&amp;rdquo; The study explores the use of vanadium dioxide (VO₂) in developing optical modulators operating at the 2 μm wavelength, offering insights into the design of efficient optical communication components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/10360477&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shamima Akter Mitu Defends Master&#39;s Thesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023-05-03-shamima-akter-mitu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023-05-03-shamima-akter-mitu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Shamima Akter Mitu for successfully defending her Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis. This achievement signifies her dedication and contribution to her area of research, marking a milestone in her academic career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconfigurable Broadband Metasurface Published</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2023-04-29-reconfigurable-broadband-metasurface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2023-04-29-reconfigurable-broadband-metasurface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A paper titled &amp;ldquo;Reconfigurable Broadband Metasurface with Switchable Functionalities in the Visible Range&amp;rdquo; has been published in Optical Materials Express. The research presents a metasurface capable of switching functionalities across the visible spectrum, enabling dynamic control over light manipulation for applications in imaging and display technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Review on Biomimicry in Nanotechnology Published</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2022-12-22-comprehensive-review-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2022-12-22-comprehensive-review-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive review titled &amp;ldquo;Biomimicry in Nanotechnology: A Comprehensive Review&amp;rdquo; has been published in Nanoscale Advances. The paper delves into how biological principles inspire the design and development of nanomaterials and devices, highlighting the intersection of biology and nanotechnology for innovative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.rsc.org/en/content/articlelanding/2023/na/d2na00571a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Click here to read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abdul Mukit Secures RISE Student Research Grant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2022-11-25-abdul-mukit-secures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2022-11-25-abdul-mukit-secures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Abdul Mukit on successfully securing funding from the RISE Student Research Grant (Call-ID: S2022-02) for his proposal &amp;ldquo;Continuous Variable Quantum Key Distribution Optimization and Enhancing an Efficient Quantum Repeater Architecture Design for Better Quantum Communication Fidelity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
