<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outreach | Q-PACERS (DSMC-RG)</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Outreach</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_f05efc27037f3153.png</url>
      <title>Outreach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobbies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/hobbies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/hobbies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;photography&#34;&gt;Photography&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be a photography enthusiast with my Nikon D5100. Now, mostly I would just use my iphone to capture photos. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/50626594@N00&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Flickr &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I taught my self to play guitar and still trying to improve my skills. I try to tab different Bangla songs as I learn them and upload them online. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ultimate-guitar.com/u/sajidmc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ultimate Guitar &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-music&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/barbaricattax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YouTube &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-youtube&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;website-development&#34;&gt;Website Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also like to hack PHP and html files for web development. I had created the new version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://eee.buet.ac.bd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Department of EEE&lt;/a&gt; website with Joomla. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bas.org.bd/credits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bangladesh Academy of Sciences&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bdsapurdue.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue BDSA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/NSAC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nanotechnology Student Advisory Council&lt;/a&gt; are some of the websites that I made. My current website is based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://picocms.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PicoCMS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, I maintain the following web projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website of the Department of EEE, BUET, made with GravCMS. I had to program 3-4 custom plugins for the website using PHP/CSS:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eee.buet.ac.bd/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eee.buet.ac.bd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My father, Late Dr. Naiyyum Choudhury&amp;rsquo;s remembrance and his works are hosted here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://naiyyum.choudhury.cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;naiyyum.choudhury.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother-in-law, Dr. Shakil Farid&amp;rsquo;s website:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shakilfarid.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shakilfarid.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOR Request</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/lor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/lor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letter of recommendation is a necessity to advance in your career. It brings me utmost joy to see our students succeed in life, and is always a pleasure to give recommendation letter to potential applicants for job or higher studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remember that I can only address your accomplishments that &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;I was actively involved in&lt;/span&gt;. Ask yourself if I would be the right person to judge your research aptitude and skills. I will try to give an &lt;strong&gt;honest&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;impartial&lt;/strong&gt; assessment, so also ask yourself if my recommendation would &lt;strong&gt;help&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;hurt&lt;/strong&gt; your chances of succeeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;If you enrolled in Masters in BUET, and have dropped out / have F grades in courses, that will also be mentioned in your LOR.&lt;/span&gt; We have to comment about the motivation of the student, so you can guess what the response of that question will be in such a case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;criteria-for-getting-recommendation&#34;&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;criteria&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Criteria for Getting Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you &lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;MUST&lt;/span&gt; meet at least one of the following descriptions/criteria before you try to make an appointment with me for recommendation request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You performed MSc/PhD research work under my supervision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final year thesis/project completed under my supervision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performed some kind of project work under my guidance/in collaboration that resulted in a peer-reveiewed publication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You successfully completed my graduate level course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are a colleague / part-time faculty member who directly took any class with me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I taught a final-year lab course that you successfully completed, and demonstrated a good project &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I served as a  member in your MSc/PhD examination committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was an external examiner of your Final year thesis/project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My undergraduate advisee &lt;sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** for serial number 6 and above, I will only give LORs to schools that have application deadline on or AFTER December 15th of the calendar year. Kindly refrain from requesting LORs for other schools**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; based on  sessional course project alone, it is diffcult to judge your motivation. However,  if a project from a theory/lab course was truly exceptional, and resulted in a publication with my approval, I will be happy to recommend you based on your capacity to perform original research/review. Only for final-year lab-course, if I was directly assigned to your section, AND you completed a project successfully in that course, I can recommend you based on your output and ability to solve complex Engineering Problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply taking an undergraduate theory course does not give the instructor sufficient capacity to judge the research aptitude of a student. As such, if you only interacted with me as a student in my theory course, unfortunately, I will not be in a position to recommend you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are currently enrolled in BUET MSc program under my supervision, please consult with me before applying. Also, consider not adding me as a recommender if your research progress is unsatisfactory. For students enrolled under other faculty members, I will only recommend you only if your current supervisor recommends. You should attach a copy of the consent in the email, otherwise I will have to personally call and confirm with him/her before giving the LOR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;list-of-eligible-students&#34;&gt;List of Eligible Students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For convenience, I am explicitly listing students who only did my only undergraduate class and would be eligible for LOR. Other students are requested not to send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 Batch - EEE 416 A1 &amp;amp; A2 (Student ID 001-065)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;17 Batch - EEE 416 A1 &amp;amp; A2 (Student ID 001-065)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18 Batch - EEE 416 A2 (Student ID 033-065)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19 Batch - 151-180 (advisee), EEE 416 (Student ID 001-33, 131-163)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limit-of-lor-request&#34;&gt;Limit of LOR Request&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my direct thesis students (undergraduate, Masters or PhD) there is no upper limit to giving LORs. For other cases, the number of LOR will be limited to 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;waiver-of-access&#34;&gt;Waiver of Access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to receive a LOR from me, you &lt;strong&gt;must Waive the right to access&lt;/strong&gt; to what I write. If you do not waive your access, I would also &lt;strong&gt;decline&lt;/strong&gt; to recommend you. I believe you should only get my recommendation if you trust my judgement sufficiently. I will, however, tell you in person, if I cannot give you a positive recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I find that the waiver is not done in an LOR form, I will copy paste the following text in the LOR form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;
&#34;The detailed policy of my LOR is elaborated in my website https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/outreach/LOR, and the candidate still chose the option of not waiving the right to access this report. 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:red&#34;&gt;
Since the applicant did not waive the right to access this report, I hereby decline to give a Letter of Recommendation. &#34;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps-to-get-lor&#34;&gt;Steps to Get LOR:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly go above to &lt;a href=&#34;#criteria&#34;&gt;Criteria for Getting Recommendation&lt;/a&gt; to check if you are eligible to get a LOR from me. If not I might not respond to your email, or just decline to recommend you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are eligible to get a LOR, Please download and fill up the &lt;a href=&#34;%5cdownloads%5cLOR_Request_Form.docx&#34;&gt;LOR_Request_Form.docx&lt;/a&gt; with your information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a single email, please send the following documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completed LOR_Request_Form.docx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your transcript (if CGPA mentioning is needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your CV (Preferrably in this format: &lt;a href=&#34;%5cdownloads%5cCV-template.docx&#34;&gt;CV Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the body of the email, please again write information of the form, upto point 4, and request for the Letter of Recommendation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_If you do not email me properly, I will simply copy and send the following text (keeping it here for my convenience, so that I can copy/paste it.) _&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reply-template-for-ineligible-students&#34;&gt;Reply template for ineligible students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:black&#34;&gt;
  Dear X, &lt;br/&gt; Thank you very much for your email. If you could kindly go to my website [https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/outreach/LOR](https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/outreach/LOR) and first check if you are eligible to receive an LOR from me. If you are eligible, please fill out the [LOR Request form](https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/downloads/LOR_Request_Form.docx) and send me the email again. &lt;br/&gt;Thank you&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reply-template-for-eligible-students&#34;&gt;Reply template for eligible students&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:black&#34;&gt;
  Dear X, &lt;br/&gt; Thank you very much for your email. If you could kindly go to my website [https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/outreach/LOR](https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/outreach/LOR) and, please fill out the [LOR Request form](https://sajid.buet.ac.bd/downloads/LOR_Request_Form.docx) and send me the email again. I will confirm receipt of the email. Start adding my email after my confirmation. 
  &lt;br/&gt; Once you finish submitting all LORs, kindly email and let me know, again, and I will try to submit all of your LORs in one go. You do not need to send me a draft LOR, just the form is sufficient.
  &lt;br/&gt; For students enrolled under other faculty members, I will only recommend you only if your current supervisor recommends. You should attach a copy of the consent in the email, otherwise I will have to personally call and confirm with him/her before giving the LOR.
  &lt;br/&gt;Thank you&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I give you consent to give LOR by replying to your email, you may put my official email address sajid(at)eee.buet.ac.bd in the application portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For convenience, please submit the LOR request of ALL the universities at once. It is much easier for me to finish the LOR submission process in one sitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I forget to submit the LOR, please send me an email reminder 1 day before the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/outreach/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/outreach/poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;link href=&#34;https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Galada:400,400i,700,700i&amp;display=swap&amp;subset=bengali&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34;&gt; 
&lt;h4 id=&#34;শনতর-সনধন&#34;&gt;শান্তির সন্ধানে&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;তান্ত্রিক জগতটার তন্দ্রা ছিড়ে&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;শকুনীর হিংস্র চোখের ফাঁদ চিরে&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;বাধ ভাঙ্গার উল্লাসে ওঠো মেতে,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ঝঞ্ঝা মাতোয়ারা এ রক্তিম ধরণীতে।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;অশান্ত ধরায় যত ভয়াল দানব,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;খঞ্জরের শিঞ্জনে আজ শিহরিত মানব!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;রক্তের হোলিতে মেতেছে জন্তু জানব-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;পিঞ্জর ভেঙ্গে ছুটে যাও শান্তির ঝান্ডা নেড়ে।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;রণাঙ্গনের কলরবে পরিশ্রান্ত এ ধরা&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;যুদ্ধের দামামা আর শুনতে চায়না তারা&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;সাদা পতাকা, সাদা পায়রা, হোক না উড্ডীন&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;পিশাচীর যত রক্তপিপাসা, হয়ে যেতে দাও লীন।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;বলদশর-সনট&#34;&gt;বাংলাদেশের সনেট&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;কত পাখি চিরকাল এসে গায় গান,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;আর কত সবুজ এই বাংলাদেশ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;রূপের যেন তার নেই কোনও শেষ-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;বাংলার রূপ করিল মন হরণ ।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;উত্তরে তার এক ভংগিল পর্বত,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;দক্ষিণে সাগরের জলের টলমল,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;চারিদিকে শুধু গাঢ় সবুজের ঢল,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;আর আছে খাল বিল নদী শতশত।&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;গ্রীষ্মে যে তার এক রুদ্র ভয়াল রূপ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;বর্ষা এসে ধোয়ায় তার দুই চরণ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;শরতে যে আছে স্নিগ্ধ কোমল স্বরূপ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;হেমন্তে তার অপূর্ব আশ্চর্জ খেয়াল,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;শীতে তার লৌহতুল্য কঠিন গড়ন,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;বসন্তে সে শোভাময়, সজীব সরস।&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
